## **Elham Mohammadi**

## | elham.mohammadi9069@gmail.com |

#### **Summary**

If you are searching for a **Data Driven Senior SEO** specialist with a **lot of coding ability** with an MA degree in E-business, **I am here**. 7 years ago I started with content marketing as I heard content is the king. I had a great passion to learn about new things which helped our business grow. While I was working on growing some keywords ranking on google, I tried my best to **improve my analytical and technical background** to become an expert SEO specialist so I **got my certification on web development** in SheCodes foundation. As a highly skilled person in search engine acquisition (SEO, SEM) having experience in **e-commerce**, **travel**, **real estate**, **online insurance** and other platform-based websites with 7 years of closely working with marketing, IT, and product teams. I have a fairly deep understanding of **Google Analytics**, **Search Console**, **Screaming Frog**, **Excel**, **SEMrush**, **Ahref**, On-page & Off-page & technical SEO. My colleagues call me **Bug Finder** as I have A deep understanding of web servers, **HTML & CSS & JS**. and I have An **lelts degree of 7.5** so I have perfect verbal and writing skills.

#### **Experience**

#### Head of SEO | 01/2022 - Present | SnappMarket-online grocery (more than 150k pages) | Tehran

- Increasing 170% in non-branded keywords within 9 months through optimizing blog posts & structure of the site.
- Owned and defined the SEO strategy of all aspects (Technical, Off-page and On-page)
- Found high impressions with low click articles and optimized them around main keywords through search intent.
- Found the best topics related to our business through analyzing the competitors contents to get more organic traffic.
- Took ownership of main KPIs and **delivered weekly reports** to my marketing manager to get more informed decisions.
- Monitored editorial team for writing the best titles, meta descriptions and being aware of keyword density.
- Did a complete SEO audit for all important E-commerce competitors such as link analysis, content quality and ...
- Recommended changes to website architecture & UX, content and linking to improve SEO positions for target KWs
- Incorporated XML sitemaps, robots.txt & JS crawling files to facilitate search engine crawling and indexing.
- Checked the **crawling and indexing process** as we had so many PLP and PDP pages to ensure that important pages were indexed and fixed Redirects resulted in 2x clicks and impressions.
- Worked with tech and product team to solve the facets and attributes problems in category pages to prevent damaging SEO and duplicate content.
- Implemented the best internal link-building strategy to ensure pages are connected together.

#### Senior Technical SEO Specialist (Project) | 1/2023 - Present | Shine Armor auto detailing | United States

- Redirected all duplicate pages on their canonical version (resolved duplicated content issues).
- Working with the tech team to make technical improvements.
- Wrote a content plan for the product and category pages to be written by the content team.

# Senior Technical SEO specialist (Project) | 05/2022 –2022/11| Shopassist-online grocery (more than 120k pages) |sydney

- Optimized html tags to ensure every page has unique values like title and robot tag and ... before construction of DOM
- Had an eye for increasing crawl budget and had a cohort of indexation ratio
- Worked on crawling and indexing process to make sure all the important pages are on SERP
- Researched and prepared doc for moving from CSR to SSR with nextjs technology
- Prepared a complete guide for pagination, facet, navigation, footer link
- Developed well-researched keyword-lists using specialized SEO tools to build SEO strategies
- Fixed SEO friendly URL structure and site structure for better navigation
- Fixed all meta tags, image SEO and created dynamic sitemap and robots txt
- Set product and breadcrumb schemas to all pages

#### Senior SEO Specialist | 09/2021 - 03/2022 (Project) | The Darl Digital Marketing Agency | California

- Analyzed and audited all clients' websites (On-page & Off-page) to address performance issues.
- Grew organic web traffic by 58% and lowered bounce rate to 25% for 3 clients through updating important contents.

- Improved pay per click (PPC) campaigns through research and identification of profitable keywords for two clients and increased their conversion by 120%. As I was responsible for SEM campaigns.
- Optimized site structure and recommended the best internal link building practices with strategy for 2 clients, resulted in 2x improvement in clicks in just 2 months.
- Provided detailed reporting and analysis on all client's website demographics and statistics using Google Analytics and Search Console, SEMrush and Aherfs and Data Studio.

#### Senior SEO & CRO Specialist | 09/2019 - 06/2021 | CleverCodes Digital Marketing Agency | Vancouver

- Optimized website and category pages for 2 clients by adding valuable content, internal link building and gained backlinks, resulted in 270% and 130% growth in organic traffic over 1 year, respectively.
- Rewrote and optimized over 1500 URLs Title tags, meta descriptions, and optimized for targeted keywords.
- Earned more than 500 high quality backlinks for 1 client and nearly 250 links for another client through promotion campaigns to improve commercial keywords ranking.
- Reviewed technical SEO issues and recommended fixes for all clients through working with Tech teams.

### SEO specialist Freelancer | 09/2018 - 10/2019 | Tivan co-working space | Tehran

- Created original SEO content and content marketing plan and implemented semantic HTML for 5 clients.
- Performed On-page, Off-page and technical SEO audits, competitors analysis for all clients.
- Decreased bounce rate up to 35% and increased Time on page up to 55% for all clients through working on UX and Content.
- Optimized over 100 blog posts for targeted KWs which resulted in more than 75% more organic traffic.
- Analysis the google analytic and search console to monitor the results and SEO metrics for all clients.
- Maintained continuous check on organic KW indexing, organic traffic and SEO metrics and optimized campaigns based on these data

#### Content Marketing Specialist (SEO) | 02/2017 - 08/2018 | BimeBazar online insurance | Tehran

- Created more than 200 blog posts with optimization for targeted keywords through understanding search intent.
- Got over 1.5M monthly visit through most important blog posts related to insurance.
- Increased over 1500% in non-branded KWs in 9 months by adding more contents to articles and gained backlinks.
- Killer content marketing strategy increased reach by over 100% and increased time on site by over 60%.
- Ran promotion campaigns in relevant websites for important blog posts and got over 100K visitors monthly.
- Increased Email open rate by 25% in 5 months by investigating the needs of customers and also personalized email messages.
- Gained so many high-quality backlinks through guest posting and advertorial contents in relevant websites to increase ranking and awareness.

#### **Certificates:**

Front-end Developer, SheCodes,2023 HTML, SoloLearn, 2022 Technical SEO, SEMrush, 2022 Content Marketing, Hubspot, 2022

#### Skills:

- HTML, CSS, (advanced)
- Python (intermediate)
- JavaScript (intermediate)

- REACT (just started)
- Off-page (Link Building) (advanced)
- On-pages Strategy (advanced)
- keyword Targeting (advanced)
- Google Analytic, Search Console, Data Studio
- Kwfinder, SEMrush, Ahrefs, Alexa, Hotjar, Nightwatch, Keyword Planner (advanced)
- Screaming Frog (advanced)

#### **Education**

MA in Entrepreneurship, E-business | University of Tehran | 09/2017 | Tehran

#### Languages

• English: lelts 7.5